# 嗨喽大家好 今天跟大家分享一个烧茄子
Hello everyone, today I'm gonna share with you a dish "Sichuan Braised Eggplant"
# 我四伯爷牙口不好
My uncle's teeth are not good enough to chew things
# 这个茄子烧软一点特别适合你的胃口噶
So tender eggplant will really suit your appetite?
# 嗯
Yes
# 我们选这个茄子的时候选这个白色比较多的
We need to choose eggplants with more in the white part
# 然后选这个颜色浅一点的
and lighter in the color
# 然后你捏一下软的再买
then pinch them, buy the soft ones
# 如果是硬的话就说明中间已经长老了
If it feels hard inside, it's too old
# 就不要再买了那个是老茄子
Don't buy it then, that's an old eggplant
# 如果我们买菜每个都去跟他捏一哈的话
If we all give a pinch when go grocery shopping
# 那个商贩要起火噶
the vendor would definitely be annoyed
# 看吗又看出来了嘛老嫩
Just watch and tell, easy
# 嗯
You're right
# 我们烧这个茄子非常简单 （重要配料）只要大蒜
This eggplant recipe is very simple. We use only garlic (as the most important ingredient)
# 多吃点蒜有好处噶 四伯爷
It's good to eat more garlic, uncle?
# 是安
Yep
# 轻轻地拍哈
Crush lightly
# 我们的烧茄子这个鱼香烧起是最安逸的
The best way to cook eggplant is with "Yuxiang leaves"
# 我们这里这个鱼香其实就是藿香
Actually, "Yuxiang" is also known as "Huoxiang"
# 再放两颗泡海椒
add two more pickled chilies
# 这个泡海椒我听到说多辣安
I heard this pickled chili is very hot
# 是辣得很呢
Yeah, extremely hot
# 这个就是我们的鱼香
That's our "Yuxiang"
# 闻起来有股特殊的香味
It has a special aroma
# 吃得来的就吃得来
People who like it can enjoy it
# 吃不来的就像不能吃香菜的人吃香菜一样 感觉这个很臭
And those who don't, just like those who dislike cilantro, feel this is very smelly
# 其实我们特别喜欢这个
Actually, we especially love it
# 这个烧鱼特别香特别好吃
It's very delicious to cook with fish
# 还有我们做豆花（蘸水）这个是少不了的
Also, it's an indispensable ingredient for making (dipping sauce of) tofu pudding
# 这个给它切一下 当那个葱花起锅的时候用
Chop it a bit. We'll add it together with scallion before serving
# 然后再切点葱葱
And then chop some scallion
# 这个鱼香吗可以说在我们四川没得哪个吃不来的
As for "Yuxiang", it's said that there's no one in Sichuan who can't handle it
# 还是有少数
Still some people can't
# 吃不来的就是极少数
But very few
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入宽油
Once the wok is hot, add Kuan You (literally "broad oil")
# 然后大火将油温烧至6成热
Then heat the oil over high flame until it reaches 180 °C
# 油温6成热之后下入切好的茄子
Add the eggplants pieces
# 开中火把茄子炸熟炸至金黄色
Fry the eggplant over medium heat until golden brown and cooked thoroughly
# 嘿 看到好安逸哦噶
Hey, it looks nice!
# 同学们这里有一个小技巧
Here's a tip for you guys
# 就是炸茄子的时候必须随时搅动让茄子均匀受热
When frying eggplant, keep stirring it in order to heat it evenly
# 如果茄子不翻动的话特别容易炸糊
If we don't stir it, eggplant will be easily overcooked
# 茄子炸到金黄之后捞出备用
After it becomes golden brown, take it out and set aside
# 然后我们把宽油倒出之后下一步开始准备炒制
Pour out the Kuan You and prepare for the next step
# 在这里应伯爷的要求加入了一些猪油
At my uncle's request, I add some lard
# 油烧热烧化之后加入切好的料头爆香
After the oil is heated and melted, add the chopped aromatics until bringing out the aroma
# 料头爆香之后加入适量的豆瓣酱炒香
Add some doubanjiang (AKA broad bean chili paste)
# 然后加入炸好的茄子
Add the fried eggplant
# 下一步直接开始调味
Next step is seasoning
# 锅中加入适量的食用盐
Add a reasonable amount of salt
# 白糖
sugar
# 味精
MSG
# 再放点酱油
A little soy sauce
# 最后加入适量的水淀粉翻炒几下
Finally add some slurry, continue to toss a few times
# 芡粉糊化之后加入鱼香叶和小葱翻炒几下即可出锅装盘
Once the sauce thickens, add Yuxiang leaves and scallions. Tossing a few times, and it can be ready to serve
# 尝哈看茄子 四伯爷
Uncle, have a taste
# 哎呀不消尝的 这个茄子都好干
Oh, no need to taste, it's pretty good
# 好干噶
Really?
# 哎呀
Ah!
# 烫哦
It's hot
# 烫得很四伯爷 你小心
Be careful! It's really hot, uncle
# 我清得到
I know
# 开玩笑 好多油哦
Kidding me? That's a lot of oil
# 嗯 可以
Hmm, good
# 如果你们家庭小灶做的话可以茄子下锅之前拍一点粉
If cooking at home, you can sprinkle some flour on the eggplant before frying
# 这样更容易熟 而且还省油
That makes it easier to cook and saves some oil
# 又嫩又香 吃起好爽口哦
It's tender and tasty
# 还很下饭
And also goes well with rice
# 安逸
Nice
# 特别是这个鱼香才入味
Especially with this Yuxiang, it's so flavorful
# 嗯
That's it
# 真的好吃这个茄子
This eggplant is really delicious
# 多吃点
Eat more
# 所以我喊你整这个茄子来干呢
That's why I told you to cook eggplants
# 比你在那个柴火灶里慢慢炒安逸
It's much better than cooking slowly on a firewood stove
# 那当然咯
Definitely
# 肯定咯
Of course
# 我们有很多粉丝做这个茄子喜欢把皮扒掉
We have a lot of fans who like to peel the eggplant when they cook it
# 其实正是要有这层皮才能够对比出里面的嫩
In fact, it is the skin that emphasizes the tenderness inside
# 我们做这个茄子因为本身是油炸的
The eggplant we cooked is deep-fried
# 然后第二次炒的时候尽量要少放油
So we should use less oil when cooking for the second time
# 因为是我伯爷喜欢吃猪油 然后我后面都放了一点点
Cuz my uncle likes lard, I put a little in it
# 好 你们喜欢的话可以试一下
OK, if you like it, just have a try
# 怕油多的话就放那个淀粉拍一下再炸
If you are afraid of a greasy taste, sprinkle some flour on the eggplants before frying
# 本期视频就到这里 拜拜
That's all for this video, bye bye